# NIHAL **ANAND**

WEB DEVELOPER

LinkedIn | GitHub | Twitter | Website

## CONTACT

647-330-1841 nihalanand@gmail.com www.nihalanand.com

# **SKILLS AND ABILITIES**

- React & jQuery
- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
- RESTful APIs
- Firebase
- JavaScript ES6+
- Version control & collaboration using Git and GitHub
- C, Python & SQL
- Responsive design
- Website accessibility requirements
- Paired programming & team-based development
- Project scope management

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Canada One Auto Group

(2019 - 2020)Marketing Videographer

Reel Six Media - Self-Employed

(2015 - 2020)

Photographer & Filmmaker

Vistek - Toronto

(2018 - 2019)

Video Sales Consultant

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

**Canadian House of Commons** Certificate of Appreciation (2016)

Recognizing work as Cinematographer on documentary 'Maple Morning' and contribution to Canadian cinema.

## **PROFILE**

I am a web developer, with extensive experience in the media production industry. My ability to communicate effectively allows me to help others bring their creative vision to life.

I create responsive, accessible and visually cohesive web applications utilizing advanced skills in HTML, (S)CSS, JavaScript, and React. My proficiency in C and Python gives me a strong base in fundamental programming concepts.

### **PROJECTS**

#### **Keanu and Who?**

#### Live | GitHub

- Search for any two actors to check if they have ever acted together
- Used React and TMDB API to compare movie credits of both actors.

# **Friendly Weather App**

### Live | GitHub

- View current weather and forecast at the user's geolocation.
- Used Vanilla JS and FETCH to combine data from freegeoip.app and OpenWeather API to return results in a responsive and dynamic app.

#### Let's Get Cooking!

#### Live | GitHub

- Search for recipes using ingredients that you have in your pantry
- Uses jQuery and AJAX to get data from the Spoonacular API.

#### **Credit Card Checker**

#### Live | GitHub

- Check the validity of a credit card number and the type of card.
- Uses jQuery & nested conditionals to check Luhn's algorithm.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Juno College of Technology**

2020 - 2021 | Front-End Web Development

- Web Dev Bootcamp, Accelerated JS, Con-Ed Web Dev

# **University of Toronto, School of Continuing Studies**

2015 - 2016 | Post-Graduate Certificate

- Digital Marketing Management

### **University of Toronto, St. George**

2008 - 2013 | Honours Bachelor's of Arts

- Cinema Studies, Media Studies, English